AHMAD SAIFUL HUDA

Purwokerto, Indonesia

+62852 2909 8083| saifulhuda020@gmail.com | ahmad-sh.vercel.app _

SUMMARY

I am an Informatics Engineering graduate with experience migrating more than 200 new devices. I have a strong interest and enthusiasm for the networking field. I have a strong basic knowledge of network concepts and protocols, and have a passion for learning further and developing my skills in managing and designing efficient networks.

EXPERIENCE

Internship IT Support | June 2018 - September 2018

DISKOMINFO JATENG | Semarang, Indonesia

My jobdesk there is network installation, troubleshoots, maintenance, and also monitoring the network with software cacti.

- · Provided assistance in maintaining and servicing network hardware components.
- · Provided assistance in identifying and diagnosing issues related to the office network infrastructure.
- Configured MikroTik router and UniFi wireless devices.
- Monitored the network's performance and health using network monitoring software, specifically Cacti.

Network Administrator | February 2020 - Present

RT/RW Net | Pekalongan, Indonesia

I am the network admin and owner of this business. starting from the installation, configuration and monitoring I did it myself this is side hustle.

- Responsible for the installation of network infrastructure, including routers, switches, access points, and cables.
- Conducted thorough troubleshooting to identify problems.
- Updated and upgraded network equipment and software as needed.

Freelance IT Engineer | August 2023 - September 2023

PT. Graha Karya Informasi | Purwokerto, Indonesia

I am responsible directly to the company's clients, even though only as a Freelance IT Engineer. I handle data backup-restore, PC settings and installation of new devices.

- Direct responsibility for communication and interaction with the company's clients, ensuring their IT needs are understood and addressed.
- Managing data backup and restoration processes, which involves safeguarding critical data and ensuring it can be recovered in case of system failures or data loss.
 - Installing and setting up new devices, such as computers and network equipment, to expand or
- upgrade the client's IT infrastructure.

Network Engineer | November 2023 - Present

PT. Net Sistem Infotama, | Jakarta, Indonesia

I My job desk includes network installation, troubleshooting, maintenance, and also network monitoring where the devices I use are Cisco and Fortinet.

- Has completed device staging according to the specified target.
- Has completed the migration of Cisco and FortiSwicth devices according to the specified target, with the fastest achievement of completing 7 racks in one night.
- Helps resolve troubleshooting by requiring a new device.
- Helped with some minor problems on the client's computer network

EDUCATION

May 2019 | Bachelor of Computer Engineering SMKN 1 SRAGI, Pekalongan

August 2023 | Informatic Engineer Institut Teknologi Telkom, Purwokerto

SKILLS

- VLAN, DHCP, Routing
- Firewall, Tunnels
- Troubleshooting and Diagnosis
- Network Performance Monitoring Teamwork
- Quality of Service
- Adaptability
- Hardware Installation Communication skills
 - Strategic thinking
 - Time Management
 - Ability to Work Under Pressure